+447742143400 cloud8421@gmail.com Flat 42, North Point, Tottenham Lane, N8 7HF London

Profile

I'm a software professional with 15 years of commercial experience in complex web applications, apis and highly available distributed systems.

I've worked both as an engineer directly building products and as a manager at different scales, with my last work experience as a CTO for an industry-leading document company.

I've given talks at various ElixirConf, Erlang Factory (San Francisco and Stockholm), the Ruby, Vim and Elixir user groups and extensively mentored and coached junior developers through different initiatives like Codebar and Rails Girls.

I'm looking for an opportunity to work with a smart team on a worthy cause.

Experience

CTO, PSPDFKIT GMBH., VIENNA (REMOTE) - SEPTEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2023

- Managed the technological strategy and organisation of a 130+ people company in its growth phase, transitioning from a bootstrapped to a PE owned structure, and leading 3 acquisitions in the process. At its peak, the engineering side of the organisation had 50+ people, dozens of products developed in many languages, both on-prem and cloud.
- Designed remote-first processes, metrics, KPIs, career framework, organisational structure, with a strong eye on keeping things as simple as possible in order not to stifle productivity and personal initiative.
- Improved the security posture of the entire company as a strategic advantage in the market.
- Mentored both managers and contributors.
- · Direct involvement with critical customers, both on a strategic level and on a crisismanagement level.

WEB TEAM LEAD, PSPDFKIT GMBH., VIENNA (REMOTE) - MAY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Lead the development, testing and support of a large web-based SDK responsible for the majority of the company's revenue.
- Grown a team from 3 people to 10, and evolved methodology so that it would adapt to different timezones and product needs.
- Managed performance reviews, individual growth and role definition.

SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER, PSPDFKIT GMBH., VIENNA (REMOTE) - DECEMBER 2018 - MAY 2020

- Development, testing, deployment and support of the Elixir-based document management solution sold by the company.
- Grown from a team of one to a team of 4, and trained junior engineers new to the technology used.
- Extended the product to break into enterprise markets.

HEAD OF ELIXIR, ERLANG SOLUTIONS LTD., LONDON - JUNE 2016 - DECEMBER 2018

 Development and architecture of highly available Elixir-based applications, interfacing with iOS, Android and Web frontends

- Preparation and delivery of advanced Elixir training material (advanced Phoenix, use
 of the OTP framework, performance and reliability)
- Community outreach via talks, conference organisation and user groups

DEVELOPER/DIRECTOR, FULLY FORGED LTD., LONDON - JULY 2015 - PRESENT

Development, deployment and production monitoring of web services, ranging from complex websites to apis and single page applications.

SENIOR DEVELOPER, NEW BAMBOO WEB DEVELOPMENT LTD. (NOW THOUGHTBOT), LONDON – 2011-JULY 2015

Development, deployment and production monitoring of a wide range of web applications, from complex, css heavy websites to rich javascript clients and high performance apis. Responsibilities included product definition through daily collaboration with clients, feature development, testing and performance tuning.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, FREELANCE, MILANO (ITALY) - 2010-2011

Javascript enhancements on small websites (interactive UI, simple scripting).

BRAND MANAGER, BLACK BEAN GAMES, VARESE (ITALY) - 2008-2011

Project management, licensing and day to day operations for a video game publisher.

Education

IULM University, Milan – MA in Cinema, TV and New Media, 2008

Skills

Strategic thinking and planning of large technological initiatives

Effective verbal and written communication to all company functions

Process design and implementation, along with related coordination and supervision

Effective delegation with tight feedback loop and focus on continuous improvement

Technical Skills

Elixir and Erlang, including major ecosystem projects

Elm, Javascript, Clojurescript and major frameworks

Rails and related ecosystem (up to Rails 4.0)

Relational databases (primarily Postgresql)

Message brokers and queuing systems (especially RabbitMQ)